freevirtualservers.com 2019-03-03

# Privacy Agreement - Free Virtual Servers

Easy Internet Solutions Ltd is committed to respecting privacy of customers and users of the our websites. We have developed this policy because we want you to feel confident about the privacy and security of your personal information. 

## Who we are

This privacy policy governs the manner in which Easy Internet Solutions Ltd (a private limited company registered in England – registration number 04953168) also hereafter referred to as "The Company", "Us" or "We" or just "Easy Internet Solutions" – a subsidiary company of Easy Internet Holdings Ltd (a private limited company registered in England – registration number 05612084) also hereafter referred to as "The Group", "group of companies" – uses, maintains and discloses information collected from customers and users of our websites (the "Data"). It does not apply to any other company or to any other company's websites even if you access them through or they are hosted by the Company. If you disclose your personal information to other companies your information will be dealt with according to their privacy practices.  
Easy Internet Solutions is registered under the Data Protection Act in the United Kingdom as a Data Controller (registration number Z8606982) and takes all reasonable care to prevent any unauthorised access to your personal information. 

## Personal Information Collection

We may request or collect personal information from online users in a variety of ways, including through online forms for ordering products and services, and other instances where users are invited to volunteer such information. "Personal information" in this privacy policy, we mean information, which identifies you as an individual, or is capable of doing so – for example, your name, address, telephone number, email address, date of birth and billing information. 

## Non-personally identifying information

We may also collect information on how users interact with our websites by using cookies and log files which may include your Internet Protocol (IP), browser "user-agent", pages viewed and other activities similar activities. 

## Personal Information Collection

We may request or collect personal information from online users in a variety of ways, including through online forms for ordering products and services, and other instances where users are invited to volunteer such information. "Personal information" in this privacy policy, we mean information, which identifies you as an individual, or is capable of doing so – for example, your name, address, telephone number, email address, date of birth and billing information. 

## Legal Basis for processing personal Information

Our legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described above will depend on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it. 

We will normally collect personal information from you only (i) where we need the personal information to perform a contract with you; (ii) where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your rights; or (iii) where we have your consent to do so. We have a legitimate interest in operating our Services and communicating with you as necessary to provide these Services, for example when responding to your queries, improving our platform, undertaking marketing, or for the purposes of detecting or preventing illegal activities. 

If we ask you to provide personal information to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contract with you, we will make this clear at the relevant time and advise you whether the provision of your personal information is mandatory or not (as well as of the possible consequences if you do not provide your personal information). 

## Your rights under GDPR

If you're a citizen of the EU, you have the following rights under the GDPR: 

  * You can update the personal data we hold on you at any time by logging into your account and updating the details as required. 
  * You can opt-out of marketing emails at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link on any marketing email we send you. 
  * You have the right to complain to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your personal information. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority. 
  * You have the right to request a copy of the data we hold on you, for free. If you wish to exercise this right, please submit a ticket to Customer Services and we can provide a copy of your account in JSON format. 

## Cookie Policy

This site uses cookies – small text files that are placed on your machine to help the site provide a better user experience. In general, cookies are used to retain user preferences, store information for things like shopping carts, and provide anonymised tracking data to third party applications like Google Analytics. As a rule, cookies will make your browsing experience better. However, you may prefer to disable cookies on this site and on others. The most effective way to do this is to disable cookies in your browser. We suggest consulting the Help section of your browser or taking a look at the About Cookies (http://www.aboutcookies.org) website which offers guidance for all modern browsers. 

If cookies aren't enabled on your computer, it will mean that your shopping experience on our website will be limited to browsing and researching; you won't be able to add products to your basket and buy them.

The list of Cookies that are currently running on our website(s): Google Analytics, Google AdWords, Social Media Share Buttons by ShareThis.com and Addthis.com

## How will we use the information

Easy Internet Solutions Ltd may use the personally identifiable information collected to contact customers regarding products and services offered by the group of companies and, as necessary to provide the products and services to the customer, our suppliers, contractors and partners. We may also use information provided for research, marketing, advertising, sales and statistical analysis. We will not in any way share this information with a third party for free or by selling it outside the Easy Internet Group of companies, unless you specifically authorise such disclosures. We will also use your information for processing your order(s) and managing and administering your account, delivering any services products or information requested by you, responding to enquiries or complaints, verifying your identity and for administering debt recoveries. 

Easy Internet Solutions Ltd may also disclose aggregate, anonymous, data based on information collected from Users to investors and potential partners. In such cases, statistical information only will be disclosed and personally identifiable data will be kept strictly confidential. If Easy Internet Solutions Ltd or a brand name is sold to a third party as a whole, the information collected from users may be transferred to the new owners.

We may also collect and use other information for internal purposes – for example, contact with our technical support or sales departments, accesses to your account and any reported violations of our terms and conditions that you or someone on your account may have committed. This is to help us fit the service to your individual needs, to help us diagnose problems you may be having and for system security.

## Disclosure of information to others

We may disclose information about you, your account to companies operated by Easy Internet Holdings Ltd, in the event we undergo re-organisation or are sold to a third party or, as necessary, to our suppliers for them to be able to supply certain items to you (such as domain name registrations). We do not sell or pass your personal information to third parties (other than as already stated) unless you have given us permission or unless it is necessary to delivery the products and services ordered or used by you. Easy Internet Solutions Ltd may also be obliged to disclose your personal information to meet any legal or regulatory requirements or obligations in accordance with applicable law. 

## Service Announcements

On occasions, it is necessary to send out service related announcements, such as maintenance and upgrade warnings. Users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. 

## Length of data retention and Data Maintenance

The time period for which we keep information varies according to what the information is used for. In some cases, there are legal requirements to keep data for a minimum period. Unless there is a specific legal requirement for us to keep the information, we will retain it for no longer than is necessary for the purposes for which the data was collected or for which it is to be further processed.  
The data may be stored on one or more databases directly or indirectly maintained by Easy Internet Solutions. We employ industry standard security measures to protect the confidentiality of the information, but whilst we cannot guarantee that any loss, misuse or alteration of data will not occur, every effort is made to prevent such occurrences. Any particularly sensitive information (such as credit card details) is encrypted prior to transmission to us and will only be stored in encrypted systems. 

Billing data is retained for 7 years, as is required by UK VAT law. 

## Access to your information

If you wish to find out what personal information Easy Internet Solutions Ltd holds about you, please tell us and give us any relevant information (such as your full name, address and internet domain names) to enable us to locate the information about you because this will speed up our reply. We may be able to provide the specific information you want without you having to make a formal request. You can make a formal request if you want to know what personal information we hold about you. In this case, please put your request in writing and send it to us enclosing a cheque for the administration fee of ten pounds sterling made payable to Easy Internet Solutions Ltd and sent to: The Data Controller, Easy Internet Solutions Ltd, Unit D, Edward House, Grange Business Park, Whetstone, Leicester, LE8 6EP.  
Please be aware that communications over the Internet, such as emails/webmails, are not secure unless they have been encrypted. Your communications may route through a number of countries before being delivered – this is the nature of the World Wide Web/Internet. We cannot accept responsibility for any unauthorised access or loss of personal information that is beyond our control. 

## Transferring your information outside the EEA

It may sometimes be necessary to transfer your personal information to companies located in countries outside of the European Economic Area. This may happen when our servers, suppliers or service providers are based outside the EEA. The data protection and other laws of these countries may not be as comprehensive as those in the UK or the EU – in these instances we will take steps to ensure that your privacy rights are respected. 

## Your responsibilities

If the information we hold about you is inaccurate, please let us know and we will make the necessary amendments and confirm that these have been made. If any of your information changes, it is your responsibility to notify us about the change as soon as possible. It is your sole responsibility to ensure that all usernames and passwords issued to you are kept safe and secure. 

## Monitoring/Recording of communications

We may monitor or record your calls, emails, text messages and other communications that may take place in accordance with UK law, and in particular for business purposes, such as for quality control and training, to prevent unauthorised use of our systems, to ensure effective systems operation and in order to prevent or detect crime. 

## Changes to our privacy policy

We may change our privacy policy from time to time or how your data is processed under the Data Protection Act. New policies will be published on our web site or listed at the UK Government's Information Commissioner.
